别骑骆驼了
Forget camels.
想象一下，驾驭着一台90英尺长的巨兽巴士
Imagine cruising through the Sahara in a 90-foot long monster bus
驰骋撒哈拉，那轮子比大老爷们还高
with wheels taller than a grown man.
不仅有豪华餐厅，邮轮般的舷窗
Complete with lounges for fine dining, portholes like an ocean liner,
更有碾碎沙丘、开辟坦途的强劲马力
and enough horsepower to crush dunes in two highways.
1932年，真有人动手造了这玩意儿
In 1932, someone actually tried to build this.
堪称世上最离谱的陆地巡洋舰
The world's most ridiculous land yacht.
后来呢？它又为何会湮没于黄沙之中？
What happened? And why did it vanish into the sand?
百年以来，火车曾是陆地霸主，以速度、舒适和奢华穿梭于列国之间
For a hundred years, trains ruled the land, crossing nations in speed, comfort, and luxury.
但火车离不开铁轨
But trains need railway tracks.
随着汽车的崛起，工程师们萌生了一个新点子
And with the rise of the motor car, engineers had a new idea.
要是能把铁路开进蛮荒之地呢
What if you could bring the railway to the wild?
既然汽车取代了马匹，那现在，也该轮到骆驼下岗了
And just as the car had replaced the horse, now it was the camel's turn.
他们管这叫“新沙漠之舟”
And they called this idea the New Ship of the Desert.
这个雄心勃勃的设计长86英尺
This was ambitiously designed to be 86 feet long,
高耸于沙漠26英尺之上
operate at 26 feet high above the desert sands,
由两台900马力的迈巴赫引擎驱动
and be propelled by twin Maybach engines, each with 900 horsepower,
能拉动超过20吨的货物
able to carry more than 20 tons of freight.
再聊聊那些巨轮
And let's talk about those giant wheels.
构想是，整个沙漠之舟的车身悬于液压弹簧的摇篮上
The idea was that the entire body of the desert ship would be suspended in a cradle of hydraulic springs,
靠着直径15英尺的巨轮翻越沙丘
with the giant wheels, 15 feet in diameter, carrying it over the dunes.
由于这玩意的惊人重量
And because of the sheer weight of the craft,
轮子基本就充当了巨型压路机，在身后压出一条路来
the wheels would essentially be acting like giant steamrollers, and creating a road behind them.
这片被压实的沙地将为当地人
This packed and crushed sand would facilitate travel for the locals,
或是后方的其他车辆提供便利
or any other vehicles following behind.
脑补一下某种护航队
Imagine some sort of convoy.
But let's just pause for a second and talk about the physics.
但咱们先打住，聊聊物理学
因为这想法固然疯狂，也不乏可取之处
Because whilst the idea was insane, and with merit,
但沙漠可不是善茬
the desert is not forgiving.
这台机器能驾驭地形没错
This machine could handle the terrain.
问题是，地形驾驭不了它
The problem is, the terrain couldn't handle it.
沙子不会被压实变成沥青
Sand doesn't compress and become asphalt.
它只会位移
It shifts.
宽轮子是管用，但它们依旧沉重且集中
Wide wheels help, but they're still heavy and concentrated.
迈巴赫驱动的坦克可不轻巧
A Maybach-powered tank is not light on its feet,
液压悬挂听着很未来
and hydraulic suspension sounds futuristic,
但你想象一下1932年在沙尘暴里修它
but imagine trying to service that in a sandstorm in 1932.
但工程师们相信，只要燃料管够
But the engineers believed that it would be able to move it around 30 miles per hour over the sand dunes,
它能在沙丘上以每小时30英里的速度跑出6000英里的续航
with a range of about 6,000 miles with adequate fuel on board.
这确实很牛了，毕竟普通汽车可跑不了6000英里
Which is very impressive indeed, considering normal cars can't do 6,000 miles.
或者说牛大了，我必须提醒你，撒哈拉沙漠从南到北也就18000英里
This is so impressive, that I have to remind you that the Sahara is only 18,000 miles top to bottom.
所以，这玩意的实际续航，你懂的
So, real range may vary of this actual craft.
至于短途旅行，我稍后会讲它们有多逆天
For shorter trips, and I'll get into the details of how crazy they were later,
速度和续航大概都只有一半
the speed and range was about half.
要控制这么个大家伙
To control such a large beast,
还得有第三台小点的，7.5升的柴油引擎来为船上所有的电子设备供电
there would be a third, smaller, 7.5 litre diesel engine that would power all of the electronics on board,
包括用于转向的液压马达
including the hydraulic motor for steering.
船上还会有一台大功率无线电台，用于穿越沙漠时通讯
And there would also be a large, powerful radio to communicate across the desert,
以及接收天气预报，跟真的轮船一样
and to receive weather reports, just like a real ship.
当然，这艘船还得依靠技艺高超的领航员观测星象
Although, the vessel would rely on skilled navigators
确保他们不会在瞬息万变的沙丘中迷失方向
to read the stars to make sure that they didn't get lost in the ever-changing sand dunes.
不过我猜你一定好奇，在船上旅行究竟是种什么体验
But of course, I bet you're wondering, what exactly would it be like to travel on board?
泥嚎，我是Found and Explained的Nick
Hello, Nick from Found and Explained here.
我们已经见识过把船开到沙漠中心的后果了
We've seen what happens when you try to put a ship in the middle of the desert.
这么说吧，后勤急得直骂娘
Let's just say, logistics can get complicated.
沙子无孔不入，骆驼会偷吃你的罐装猪油
Sand gets everywhere, camels get into your canned lard,
还有那高温，哎呦我，烤箱都跟冰柜似的
and the heat, boy, it makes an oven seem like an icebox.
经营生意要是没趁手的工具，感觉也差不多
Running a business without the right tools can feel the same.
你手忙脚乱地应付网站、销售、发票、邮件，全在不同的地方
You're juggling websites, sales, invoices, emails, all in different places,
指望它们能奇迹般地运转起来
hoping it somehow floats.
广告空降5:01
因为这艘沙漠之舟实在太高了
Because this desert ship was so darn tall,
乘客的垂直空间相当充裕，足足有三层主甲板
there was actually plenty of vertical space for passengers, with three main decks.
最下层甲板有两个引擎室，一前一后
The lowest deck would have twin engine rooms, one at the front and one at the back,
里面的迈巴赫引擎会像钢铁骆驼般咆哮
that would roar like steel camels with those Maybach engines.
而十一个可怜的灵魂，也就是船员
Whilst eleven poor souls, or crew,
生活在它们之间一个摇摇晃晃的金属盒子里，舷窗外只有虚无
lived in a swaying metal box slung between them, with portholes to nowhere.
两侧是凹进去的存储区，装着额外的货物
On the sides, there would be concave storage recesses that would contain extra cargo,
或是一些履带式摩托巴士，用于短途旅行和远足
or the multiple caterpillar motorbuses that would be used for short range trips and excursions.
可惜，关于这些小艇的细节我所知不多
Unfortunately, I don't have much in the way of the details of the smaller craft.
我只知道它们有履带，采用了某种半履带设计
All I know is that they had a caterpillar, and had sort of a half-track design,
就像我们后来在1940年代看到的那样
that we'd see later in the 1940s.
这层甲板上还有通往地面的梯子和升降机
Also on this deck, there would be ladders and lifts to access the ground.
不过我猜，在特定的终点站
Although I imagine, at specific terminals,
应该会有个脚手架让乘客进入客舱甲板
there would be a scaffolding for the passengers to access the actual passenger decks,
而不是费劲爬上爬下
rather than climbing up and down.
第二层是下等客舱
The second level would have a lower-class passenger quarters,
毕竟，在900马力隆隆作响的引擎上晃着吊床，这才是奢华旅行的真谛嘛
because nothing screams luxury travel like swaying hammocks above a rumbling 900-horsepower engine.
还有雪茄休息室和后部餐厅
As well as the cigar lounge and the rear dining saloon,
当你在炎热的沙漠中巡航时，那氛围简直绝了
which would be a total vibe as you cruise through the hot desert.
这里也有一对凹槽用来放货，主要是食物和水
There would also be a twin set of recesses here for cargo as well, primarily the food and water.
不提水也是不行啊，因为这玩意居然还有抽水马桶
And yes, I do need to talk about the water, because this thing also had flushable plumbing.
1932年，在沙漠里上厕所
There would be a toilet in the desert in 1932.
你就知道他们对这个奢华的理念有多认真了
That's how serious they took the luxury with this idea.
然后在顶层甲板——唯一一个完全不受车轮间隙影响的甲板
And then on the top deck, the only one of which was actually free of the wheel clearance,
设有私人的头等客舱，还有一个可以漫步观景的走廊
it had the private first-class passenger cabins, and a promenade to stroll around for the views.
这基本上就是个让你在穿越撒哈拉时
Essentially, this was a deck to walk around and contemplate your life choices
在这座巨轮酒店上踱步并思考人生的甲板
as you cross the Sahara in a giant wheeled hotel.
我不知道为什么那时候那么多机器都有长廊，我们在飞艇上也见过
I don't know why so many machines back then had promenades, we saw them in the flying boats,
但我真心希望它们能回归
but I do wish that they would come back.
这些头等舱据说也将是奢华的巅峰
These first-class cabins were also apparently going to be the pinnacle of opulence,
堪比东方快车等著名客运列车，以及，我引用一下
rivaling that of the famous passenger trains like the Orient Express, and I quote,
“最高级的普尔曼车厢”
the finest Pullman cars.
而且它会以某种方式人工制冷来对抗太阳的炙烤
And it would be somehow artificially cool to combat the sun's rays.
1932年的空调，似乎是吧
Aircon in 1932, it seems.
但我稍后会解释这背后的科学道理
But I'll explain the science behind that in a moment.
在整个船的中间，有一个楼梯间
In the middle of this entire craft, there was a stairwell,
乘客可以像在游轮上一样爬上甲板
so passengers could climb the decks like a cruise liner,
从引擎层一路向上，穿过雪茄休息室，直到星光熠熠的长廊
coming up from the engine level all the way to the cigar lounge to the starlit promenade.
然后，为了让它真正成为一艘沙漠之舟
Then to really make it a ship of the desert,
在最顶上有一个艉楼甲板，上面有控制室和船长室
on the very top there was a poop deck that had the control room and the captain's quarters.
在这里，人类历史上最懵圈的11名水手
Here, the 11 most confused sailors in human history
可以操作这艘船，运载多达56名乘客穿越沙漠
could operate and transport up to 56 passengers across the desert,
不过如果是短途的话
although for shorter distances,
这艘陆地之舟也能以不那么精致的奢华，搭载100到300名三等舱乘客
it was possible for the land ship to carry over 100 to 300 third-class passengers in less refined luxury.
当然，因为这将是一趟时速15英里，穿越沙漠的短途酷热之旅
And because this would be a short, hot 15 miles per hour trip over the desert,
我猜很多三等舱乘客宁愿选择骑骆驼
I imagine many of those third-class passengers would have rather taken the camel instead.
那么，为什么我们从未见过这艘史诗级的陆地巨舰呢
So why did we never get this epic monster of a land ship?
你应该扪心自问的第一个问题是
So the first question you have to ask yourself,
这个点子是哪位神人大能想出来的？
who was mad enough to dream up all of this?
梦到啥说啥属于是
Who wakes up one day and says,
“要是东方快车能兼职当个压路机呢？”
what if the Orient Express could moonlight as a steamroller?
所有鬼点子都少不了魔丸的事，这个也是
Well, behind every mad idea is a mad inventor, and this story was no different.
来认识一下这位高丸，来自德国的Christian Bischoff Johannes
Meet prolific innovator, Christian Bischoff Johannes from Germany,
高产魔丸
他不仅想取代骆驼，还想改变1930年代世界上的许多其他事物
who not only wanted to replace the camel, but change a lot of different things in the 1930s world.
我现在意识到，说“1930年代想改变世界的德国人”
And I now realize saying German who wanted to change the world in the 1930s
可能会让你想到1930年代另一群德国人，也许是某个政治团体
may make you think of a certain other group of German people in perhaps a political group,
我说白了你白说了，还真没纳粹啥事儿
but believe it or not, the Nazis were not involved in this case.
这位魔丸在他的职业生涯中，实际上创造了许多发明
A humble innovator would actually go on to create many inventions throughout his career,
比如一种通用的广告语音设备，本质上是一种交互式听写机
such as a generic advertising speech device, which was essentially an interactive dictation machine
可以突出显示价格和促销信息，很像我们今天的电视
that would highlight prices and sales, much like the TVs that we have today.
但他的另一项发明就很激进了
But one of his other inventions was really radical.
那是一顶能给你降温的帽子
It was a hat that could cool you down.
实际上，这个想法是通过一种轻质的、易挥发的化学物质来冷却身体
Actually, it was the idea to cool the body by means of a light, volatile chemical,
而非——举例来说——凉风
instead of, say, a cool breeze.
就是说啥呢，你把手腕或头部伸进这个装置
The idea was that you would put your wrist or head into this device,
一种特殊的化学物质，由于吸热反应而触感凉爽
and a special chemical, which are cool to the touch due to an endothermic reaction,
会冷却你的血液，进而冷却你的全身
would cool your blood and soon your whole body,
但装置的屏障又会防止它造成伤害
but prevented from causing harm by the barrier of the device.
不赖
Neat.
然后他把这个想法应用到了船舱上
He would then take this idea and apply it to the cabin of a ship,
再然后他意识到，要是我们把它放到陆地上呢
and then he would realize, what if we put it on land?
于是，这就成了他的毕生杰作，沙漠之舟
So this would become his magnum opus, the ship of the desert.
他对这个概念自我感觉相当良好，以至于他费尽心思去申请专利
He was so confident with this concept that he went out of his way to patent it
各个国家各个语言申了个遍
in as many territories and languages as possible.
在所有拥有殖民地的国家都申请了专利
Patents for all countries with colonial possessions.
他还规划了这个概念的最终演变
And he planned eventual evolutions of this concept,
比如一个可以在陆地和水上行驶的两栖版本
such as an amphibious version that could travel on both land and water,
而且比较扯的是，他还为它在水下行驶的想法申请了专利
and weirdly, also patented the idea for it to travel underwater.
真的，这家伙是奔着把这项目送上月球去的
Really, this guy saw this project going to the moon.
点点关注，揭秘水下陆巡的大结局
And you could subscribe for my eventual video on what happened to underwater land ships.
为了寻找投资者，他真造了个比例模型并花五年时间在世界各地巡回展示
To seek investors, he actually built a scale model and shopped it around the world for five years
看看有没有冤种接这个项目
to see if anyone was keen to build it.
它甚至登上了《现代机械与发明》的封面
It even made the cover of modern mechanics and inventions.
它充满了低俗小说的能量
It had pure Pulp Fiction energy,
有着霓虹绿的油漆、巨大的前灯
with neon green paint, giant headlights,
还有一个直接从泰坦尼克号上搬来的、带着探照灯的船长塔
and a captain's tower straight off the Titanic with searchlights.
这玩意与其说是工程手册
It was less engineering manual
不如说是给那些“喝汽油的纯爷们”看的科幻漫画
and more sci-fi comic for the men who drink gasoline.
在大萧条和法西斯主义抬头的背景下
And in the midst of the Great Depression and rising fascism,
这算得上一个关于进步与和平的梦想，乐观得近乎可笑
this was a dream of progress and peace, almost laughably optimistic.
也许这不仅仅是一辆载具
And maybe this wasn't just a vehicle.
也许它是一个象征，象征着殖民野心，象征着不可能的希望
Maybe it was a symbol, one of colonial ambition, of impossible hope,
或者是一个人光荣的、滚滚向前的狂热梦想
or one man's glorious rolling fever dream.
但随着战争的阴云逼近
But with war on the horizon,
没人有闲工夫琢磨和平、友谊，或者巨型豪华陆地巡洋舰这种蠢点子
no one had time for silly ideas like peace, friendship, or giant luxury land ships.
就这样，随着世界陷入战争，这个想法也终结了
And just like that, the idea ended as the world descended to war.
不过我确实好奇，他是否考虑过给它装上几门炮
Although I do wonder if he had given any thought to sticking some guns on it.
如果他把它武器化了，德国人在埃及和北非的战斗将会截然不同
The battle for Egypt and North Africa for the Germans would have gone very differently indeed, if he had weaponized it.
要不关注一下，未来也许就能看到那个
So maybe subscribe to see that story of the world of giant impossible
关于“巨大且虚幻的陆地战舰”的故事了
to build land battleships.
但装置的屏障又会防止它造成伤害。很妙
然后他把这个想法应用到了船舱上
再然后他意识到，要是我们把它放到陆地上呢
于是，这就成了他的毕生杰作，沙漠之舟
他对这个概念是如此自信，以至于他费尽心思去申请专利
在尽可能多的地区，用尽可能多的语言
为所有拥有殖民地的国家申请专利
他还规划了这个概念的最终演变
比如一个可以在陆地和水上行驶的两栖版本
而且奇怪的是，他还为它在水下行驶的想法申请了专利
真的，这家伙是奔着把这项目送上月球去的
你可以订阅我最终关于水下陆地巡洋舰结局的视频
为了寻找投资者，他真的造了一个比例模型，并花了五年时间在世界各地巡回展示
看看是否有人热衷于建造它
它甚至登上了《现代机械与发明》的封面
它充满了低俗小说的能量，有着霓虹绿的油漆、巨大的前灯
还有一个直接从泰坦尼克号上搬来的、带着探照灯的船长塔
这玩意与其说是工程手册，不如说是给那些“喝汽油的纯爷们”看的科幻漫画
在大萧条和法西斯主义抬头的背景下
这是一个关于进步与和平的梦想，近乎可笑的乐观
也许这不仅仅是一辆车
也许它是一个象征，象征着殖民野心，象征着不可能的希望
或者是一个人光荣的、滚动的狂热梦想
但随着战争的阴云逼近，没人有闲工夫琢磨和平、友谊，或者巨型豪华陆地巡洋舰这种蠢点子
就这样，随着世界陷入战争，这个想法也终结了
不过我确实好奇，他是否考虑过给它装上几门炮
如果他把它武器化了，德国人在埃及和北非的战斗将会截然不同